<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Amy Fox</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Amy Fox</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>bactcountr R package for automatically calculating CFUs</title>
      <link>/project/bactcountr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bactcountr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;bactcountr is an R package that provides an automated way to calculate Colony Forming Units (CFUs) based on the dilutions used. It then calculates statistical significance and plots the final results. All of the code for this package can be found on my github page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aef1004/bactcountr&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aef1004/bactcountr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated nanostring analysis</title>
      <link>/project/nanostring-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nanostring-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NanoString nCounter is a technology used to assess gene expression data. I was recently approached by a colleague that spent weeks copy and pasting data into GraphPad to analyze the the data. In response, I built a pipeline that performs automated statistical analysis for the Nanostring data. The pipeline reads in and cleans the data that contains hundreds of genes per study animal. It then tests each gene-mouse group pair for normality, similar variances, and then performs the appropriate statistical test (t-test or Wilcox Mann-Whitney) based on the results. This pipeline reduces analysis time from 1 week to under 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyto-feature engineering- A novel pipeline for flow cytometry analysis</title>
      <link>/project/cyto-feature-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cyto-feature-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flow cytometers can now analyze up to 50 parameters per cell and millions of cells per sample;
however, conventional methods to analyze data are subjective and time-consuming. To address these
issues, we have developed a novel analysis pipeline to identify a plethora of cell populations efficiently.
Coupled with feature engineering and immunological context, researchers can immediately extrapolate
novel discoveries through easy-to-understand plots. The R-based pipeline uses Fluorescence Minus One
(FMO) controls or distinct population differences to develop thresholds for positive/negative marker
expression. The continuous data is transformed into binary data, capturing a positive/negative biological
dichotomy often of interest in characterizing cells. Next, a filtering step refines the data, from all
identified cell phenotypes to populations of interest. The data can be partitioned by immune lineages and
statistically correlated to other experimental measurements. The pipeline’s modular nature allows
customization of statistical testing, adoption of alternative initial gating steps, and incorporation of otherdatasets. Validation of this pipeline through manual gating of two datasets (murine splenocytes and
human whole blood) confirmed its accuracy in identifying even rare subsets. Lastly, this pipeline can be
applied in all disciplines utilizing flow cytometry regardless of cytometer or panel design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Website in R Blogdown</title>
      <link>/project/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the Academia Hugo theme developed by Michael Vahn, I have developed this website using R blogdown, Github, and the web-service Netlify. All of the code for this website can be found on my github page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aef1004/blogdown_academia_2020&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aef1004/blogdown_academia_2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
