<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Amy Fox</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Amy Fox</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated nanostring analysis</title>
      <link>/project/nanostring-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nanostring-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NanoString nCounter is a technology used to assess gene expression data. I was recently approached by a colleague that spent weeks copy and pasting data into GraphPad to analyze the the data. In response, I built a pipeline that performs automated statistical analysis for the Nanostring data. The pipeline reads in and cleans the data that contains hundreds of genes per study animal. It then tests each gene-mouse group pair for normality, similar variances, and then performs the appropriate statistical test (t-test or Wilcox Mann-Whitney) based on the results. This pipeline reduces analysis time from 1 week to under 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyto-feature engineering- A novel pipeline for flow cytometry analysis</title>
      <link>/project/cyto-feature-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cyto-feature-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flow cytometers can now analyze up to 50 parameters per cell and millions of cells per sample;
however, conventional methods to analyze data are subjective and time-consuming. To address these
issues, we have developed a novel analysis pipeline to identify a plethora of cell populations efficiently.
Coupled with feature engineering and immunological context, researchers can immediately extrapolate
novel discoveries through easy-to-understand plots. The R-based pipeline uses Fluorescence Minus One
(FMO) controls or distinct population differences to develop thresholds for positive/negative marker
expression. The continuous data is transformed into binary data, capturing a positive/negative biological
dichotomy often of interest in characterizing cells. Next, a filtering step refines the data, from all
identified cell phenotypes to populations of interest. The data can be partitioned by immune lineages and
statistically correlated to other experimental measurements. The pipeline’s modular nature allows
customization of statistical testing, adoption of alternative initial gating steps, and incorporation of otherdatasets. Validation of this pipeline through manual gating of two datasets (murine splenocytes and
human whole blood) confirmed its accuracy in identifying even rare subsets. Lastly, this pipeline can be
applied in all disciplines utilizing flow cytometry regardless of cytometer or panel design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Experimental Evaluation of Gar Scale Arrow Points</title>
      <link>/project/gar-scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gar-scales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been speculated that gar scales could have been used as arrow points in the Stone Age, especially in lithic-poor areas. I explored the usage and feasibility of gar scales as potential arrow points. I predicted that gar scales are feasible arrows point, and most will not break when used. To test this hypothesis, I shot a series of gar scale arrow points at an animal carcass using a calibrated cross bow. Based on my observations that the majority of the gar scales did not break and the fractures that did ensue usually occurred on the points with very thin serrated edges, my results can aid in the identification of potential alligator gar scale arrows at archeological sites. Through this project, I learned how to perform extensive literature searches on a neglected subject, execute a research project, and I wrote a paper that was published in the Journal of Houston Archeological Society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lace-Tension Controlled Compression Sock</title>
      <link>/project/compression-sock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/compression-sock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Rice University, my senior design team developed an adjustable compression sock that is easier to don and doff. Chronic venous disorders (CVDs) affect 40% of the U.S. population, or 128 million people, in the United States alone. Out of the patients who are prescribed medical-grade compression socks, 63% do not wear them daily, because they are difficult to put on and uncomfortable to wear. Our goal was to develop a durable, comfortable compression sock that can be easily donned and delivers the necessary amount of pressure to mitigate the effects of CVD and reduce patient noncompliance. Our technology utilizes a clutch reel and corset-lacing so that it is easily wearable, comfortable, and delivers the necessary pressure. We obtained IRB approval and tested our compression sock on patients from 50-60 years old. We received many awards through presenting our design at many showcases and poster presentations, and ultimately submitted a patent for our design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Website in R Blogdown</title>
      <link>/project/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the Academia Hugo theme developed by Michael Vahn, I have developed this website using R blogdown, Github, and the web-service Netlify. All of the code for this website can be found on my github page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aef1004/blogdown_academia_2020&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aef1004/blogdown_academia_2020&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
